A Guide to the Fries Textile Plant Records, 1900-1988
Special Collections, Virginia Tech
- Series V: Production Materials, 1904-1981
  - Daily Supply Usage (folder 3 of 3), 1979-1980 (Box 126, Folder 5)
  - Learner, Make Up Overtime Double Over and Instructor Pay, 1978-1979 (Box 126, Folder 6)
  - Learner, Make Up Overtime Double Over and Instructor Pay (folder 1 of 2), 1980 (Box 126, Folder 7)
  - Learner, Make Up Overtime Double Over and Instructor Pay (folder 2 of 2), 1980 (Box 126, Folder 8)
  - Learner Pay, 1980-1981 (Box 126, Folder 9)
  - Energy Budgets and Reports, 1976-1981 (Box 126, Folder 10)
  - Energy Budgets and Invoices, 1978 (Box 126, Folder 11)
  - Energy Reports, Budgets, and Invoices, 1979 (Box 126, Folder 12)
  - Energy Reports, Budgets, and Invoices, 1980 (Box 126, Folder 13)
  - Energy Reports, Budgets, and Invoices, 1981 (Box 126, Folder 14)
  - Consolidated Inventory, 1979-1980 (Box 126, Folder 15)
  - Consolidated Inventory, 1980-1981 (Box 126, Folder 16)
  - Graphs, 1979-1980 (Box 126, Folder 17)
  - Inventory Packing Materials - Oil Sizing, 1980 (Box 126, Folder 18)
  - Labor Realization Analysis, 1980 (Box 126, Folder 19)
  - Absenteeism and Turnover, 1980-1981 (Box 126, Folder 20)
  - PIP Reports, 1981 (Box 126, Folder 21)
  - Knitting Records, 1969-1970 (Box 119)
  - Test Records?, 1969-1970 (Box 133)
  - Knitting Daily Averages, March- July 1970 (Box 133)
  - Repairs?, 1970 (Box 55)
  - Test Records, 1970-1971 (Box 133)
  - 1971 Knitting Daily Averages, February 1971- October 1971 (Box 133)
  - Fabric Tests?, 1971-1972 (Box 133)
  - Test Records, 1972-1973 (Box 133)
  - Inventory, Beams, Permax, Wax, Starch, 1974 (Box 135, Folder 56)
  - Inventory, Yarn Mill Inprocess (folder 1 of 4), 1974 (Box 135, Folder 57)
  - Inventory, Yarn Mill Inprocess (folder 2 of 4), 1974 (Box 135, Folder 58)
  - Inventory, Yarn Mill Inprocess (folder 3 of 4), 1974 (Box 135, Folder 59)
  - Inventory, Yarn Mill Inprocess (folder 4 of 4), 1974 (Box 135, Folder 60)
  - Inventory, Cloth Room Stock In Progress, 1974 (Box 135, Folder 61)
  - Inventory, Study Summary, 1974 (Box 135, Folder 62)
  - Inventory, Weave Room Stock on Looms, 1974 (Box 135, Folder 63)
  - Inventory, Yarn Mill In Process (folder 1 of 2), 1974 (Box 135, Folder 64)
  - Inventory, Yarn Mill In Process (folder 2 of 2), 1974 (Box 135, Folder 65)
  - Waste Book, 1977 (Box 58)
  - Production Records, 1977-1978 (Box 116)
  - Fabric Tests (Box 133)
  - Cotton Book, 1915- 1933 (Box 129)
  - Diehl Drive Section - CB (Tray No. 3) Slide Deck, September 3, 1976 (Box 157)
  - Transfer Motion Section - BG (Tray No. 10) Slide Deck, September 3, 1976 (Box 157)
  - Introduction Section - AA Unit - A (Tray No. 1) Slide Deck, September 3, 1976 (Box 157)
  - Prot. Motion/ Shuttle Boxing/ 2nd Positioning Shuttle/ Picking Motion/ Checking Motion (Tray No. 6) Slide Deck, September 3, 1976 (Box 157)
  - Filling Feeder/ Thread Cutter/ Shuttle Eye Section B.H. Temples Section BI (Tray No. 11) Slide Deck (Box 158)
  - Cam Shaft/ Rocker Shaft Section AD/ 2nd Lay Section - AG (Tray No. 5) Slide Deck, September 3, 1976 (Box 158)
  - Center Fork Section BI/ Warp Stop Motion Section BF (Tray No. 9) Slide Deck, September 3, 1976 (Box 158)
  - Not For Fries/ Drive Section - AB - 1 - 96 (Tray No. 2) Slide Deck, September 3, 1976 (Box 158)
  - Let Off Section BC/ Side Fork Section BD (Tray No. 8) Slide Deck, September 3, 1976 (Box 158)
  - Care "Before" + After Slides, 1981- 1982 (Box 159)
  - Shuttles Section BA/ Take Up Wind Up Section BB (Tray No. 7) Slide Deck, September 3, 1976 (Box 159)
  - Tape Selvage Temples Section - CA+ BJ (Tray No. 12) Slide Deck (Box 159)
  - 1st Crank Shaft Section - AC - 1 - 54/ 2nd Shedding Motion Section - AE - 1 - 78 (Tray No. 4) Slide Deck, September 3, 1976 (Box 159)
- Series VI: Legal Records, 1900-1977
  - Deeds, contracts, applications for rights, and drafts of same, 1900 (Box 68)
  - 98 Copy of Lease to New River Grocery, 1905 (Box 128, Folder 16)
  - Mill Reports and Other Data, 1910-1925 (Box 128, Folder 29)
  - Indemnity Bond, 1937 (Box 128, Folder 19)
  - Data Pertaining to Pay Increase Request, 1944 (Box 128, Folder 27)
  - Rate Data Pertaining to Revisions, 1945 (Box 128, Folder 28)
  - Data for Increase in Rates of Pay, 1945 (Box 128, Folder 26)
  - Historical Background Town of Fries, 1953 (Box 128, Folder 25)
  - A-25 Legal Records, 1959-1961 (Box 128, Folder 15)
  - A-2 Corrected Calls Blair Addition, April 1966 (Box 128, Folder 24)
  - D-1 Legal Description and Plat of Property Conveyed to Y.M.C.A., 1972 (Box 128, Folder 21)
  - D-2 Legal Description and Plat of Property Conveyed to James E. Robinson, Jr., 1973 (Box 128, Folder 22)
  - D-3 Land Conveyances, 1973 (Box 128, Folder 23)
  - D-4 Description of Parcels 1-5, 1973 (Box 128, Folder 20)
  - Sales Yarn Contracts, 1977 (Box 68)
  - B-12 Copy of Deed for Right of Way to Va Dept. of Highways (Box 128, Folder 17)
  - Copy of Deed to Wiley Roop (Box 128, Folder 18)
  - Copies of Deeds (Box 145)
  - Copies of Deeds (Box 145)
  - Copies of Deeds and Conveyances (Box 151)
- Series VII: Blueprints, 1901-1974
  - Sheet No. 1 Foundation Plan of Store House, May 1901 (Box 120, Folder 2)
  - Sheet No. 2 First Floor Plan of Store House, May 1901 (Box 120, Folder 2)
  - Sheet No. 3 Second Floor Plan of Store House, May 1901 (Box 120, Folder 2)
  - Sheet No. 4 Third Floor Plan of Store House, May 1901 (Box 120, Folder 2)
  - Sheet No. 5 Fourth Floor Plan of Store House, May 1901 (Box 120, Folder 2)
  - Sheet No. 6 Roof Plan of Store House, May 1901 (Box 120, Folder 2)
  - Sheet No. 7 Sections of Store House, May 1901 (Box 120, Folder 2)
  - Sheet No. 8 Elevation of Store House, May 1901 (Box 120, Folder 2)
  - Plans for Stonework Around Mill, May 1901 (Box 121, Folder 1)
  - Sheet No. 1. Plans and Details of the Dam and Gates, May 1901 (Box 122, Folder 1)
  - Sheet No. 1 Plans and Details of the Dam and Gates, May 1901 (Box 122, Folder 2)
  - Sheet No. 1. Plans and Details of the Dam and Gates, May 1901 (Box 122, Folder 2)
  - Sheet No. 3 Details of the Head Gate Walls, May 1901 (Box 122, Folder 2)
  - Sheet No. 4 Plan of Stone Foundations for the Mill Buildings, May 1901 (Box 122, Folder 2)
  - Sheet No. 15 Full Size Detail of Wrought Iron, May 1901 (Box 121, Folder 3)
  - Sheet No. 16 Elevations of Doors, May 1901 (Box 121, Folder 3)
  - Sheet No. 18 Details and Elevations of Windows, May 1901 (Box 121, Folder 3)
  - Cross Section Thro' Canal, June 1901 (Box 122, Folder 2)
  - Revised Sheet No. 5 Elevations and Sections Showing Stonework Around the Mill Buildings and Wheel House, June 1901 (Box 121, Folder 1)
  - Detail Plan of Wheel House for Washington Mills, June 1901 (Box 120, Folder 3)
  - Sheet No. 6 Plan of First Floor of Mill, July 1901 (Box 122, Folder 3)
  - Sheet No. 8. Plan of Third Floor of Mill, July 1901 (Box 122, Folder 3)
  - Sheet No. 9. Plan of Fourth Floor of Mill, July 1901 (Box 122, Folder 3)
  - Sheet No. 11 Sections of Buildings, July 1901 (Box 121, Folder 3)
  - Sheet No. 7. Plan of Second Floor of Mill, August 1901 (Box 122, Folder 3)
  - Map of Properties In Boundary Conveyed to Washington Mills, 1901 (Box 120, Folder 2)
  - Sheet No. 20 Full Size Details of Windows ad Doors for the Main Elevator Towers [missing], 1901 (Box 121, Folder 3)
  - Map of Properties in Boundry Conveyed to Washington Mills Company, 1901-1948 (Box 122, Folder 2)
  - Photocopies of Blueprints, 1901-1974 (Box 122, Folder 4)
  - Plan Showing Location of Sprinklers and Hydrants, February 1902 (Box 121, Folder 2)
  - Plan Showing Location of Sprinklers, February 1902 (Box 121, Folder 2)
  - Sheet No. 1A First Floor Plan of Shafting, March 1902 (Box 121, Folder 2)
  - Sheet No. 2A. Plan of Machinery on Second Floor, March 1902 (Box 121, Folder 2)
  - Sheet No. 3A Third Floor Plan of Shafting and Machinery, March 1902 (Box 121, Folder 2)
  - Detail of Timber Work at Crest of New Dam Across New River, March 1902 (Box 121, Folder 2)
  - Plan Showing Location of Sprinklers, February 1903 (Box 121, Folder 2)
  - Sheet No. 1 First and Second Floor Plans of Addition, August 1919 (Box 120, Folder 3)
  - Sheet No. 2 Third and Fourth Floor Plans of Addition, August 1919 (Box 120, Folder 3)
  - Sheet No. 3 Roof Plan, August 1919 (Box 121, Folder 2)
  - Sheet No. 3 Roof Plan of Addition, August 1919 (Box 121, Folder 2)
  - Sheet No. 4 Sections of Addition, August 1919 (Box 120, Folder 3)
  - Sheet No. 5 Elevations of Addition, August 1919 (Box 121, Folder 1)
  - Sheet No. 5 Elevations of Addition, August 1919 (Box 121, Folder 3)
  - Hydrographic Survey of Mill Pond on New River, March 1922 (Box 122, Folder 1)
  - Two Electric Freight Elevators, May 1932 (Box 122, Folder 1)
  - Warehouse, November 1952 (Box 122, Folder 1)
  - Plot Plan of Area Located North of Warehouse and Office and South of Highway No. 94, August 1964 (Box 121, Folder 1)
  - "Preliminary" Plant Layout Site No. 1, June 1967 (Box 120, Folder 1)
  - Preliminary Plant Layout Site No. 2, June 1967 (Box 120, Folder 1)
  - Plant Layout Site No. 3, July 1967 (Box 120, Folder 1)
  - Cross Section of Old Part of Main Mill Wood Beam Construction, November 1967 (Box 121, Folder 3)
  - Cross Section of Old Part of Main Mill Wood Beam Construction, November 1967 (Box 121, Folder 3)
  - End View of Cross Section of Mail Mill Referred to as New End- All Floors Level with Floors in Old Mill, November 1967 (Box 121, Folder 3)
  - Refrigeration Room and Cooling Tower Plans and Elevations, January 1970 (Box 121, Folder 4)
  - Refrigeration Room and Cooling Tower Column Schedule and Details, January 1970 (Box 121, Folder 4)
  - Refrigeration Room and Cooling Tower Plans and Elevations, January 1970 (Box 121, Folder 4)
  - Refrigeration Room and Cooling Tower Column Schedule and Details, January 1970 (Box 121, Folder 4)
  - Plan of 12KV. Service to Unit Substation and New Location of 2400 Volt Circuits, March 1970 (Box 121, Folder 1)
  - Refrigeration Room and Cooling Tower Addition Plumbing Floor Plan, March 1970 (Box 121, Folder 4)
  - Site Plan, March 1970 (Box 121, Folder 4)
  - Refrigeration Room and Cooling Tower Addition Floor Plan - Sections and Details, March 1970 (Box 121, Folder 4)
  - Refrigeration Room and Cooling Tower Addition Roof Plan - Elevations and Details, March 1970 (Box 121, Folder 4)
  - Refrigeration Room and Cooling Tower Foundation Plan and Details, March 1970 (Box 121, Folder 4)
  - Refrigeration Room and Cooling Tower Floor Plan and Details, March 1970 (Box 121, Folder 4)
  - Site Plan, March 1970 (Box 121, Folder 4)
  - Refrigeration Room and Cooling Tower Addition Floor Plan - Sections and Details, March 1970 (Box 121, Folder 4)
  - Refrigeration Room and Cooling Tower Addition Roof Plan - Elevations and Details, March 1970 (Box 121, Folder 4)
  - Refrigeration Room and Cooling Tower Foundation Plan and Details, March 1970 (Box 121, Folder 4)
  - Refrigeration Room and Cooling Tower Floor Plan and Details, March 1970 (Box 121, Folder 4)
  - Refrigeration Room and Cooling Tower Column Schedule and Details, January 1971 (Box 121, Folder 4)
  - Phase 1A Transformer Yard Plan, January 1973 (Box 120, Folder 4)
  - Phase 1A Single Line Diagram and Details, January 1973 (Box 120, Folder 4)
  - Washer Tower Addition, January 1974 (Box 120, Folder 1)
  - Site and Piping Plan, January 1974 (Box 120, Folder 1)
  - Washer Tower Addition Plans, Sections, and Details, January 1974 (Box 120, Folder 1)
  - Washer Tower Addition 2nd and 3rd Floor Framing Plan, January 1974 (Box 120, Folder 1)
  - Washer Tower Addition Elevations, January 1974 (Box 120, Folder 1)
  - Washer Tower Addition Column Schedule and Details, January 1974 (Box 120, Folder 1)
  - Washer Tower Addition Floor Plans, January 1974 (Box 120, Folder 1)
  - Washer Tower Addition Floor Plan and Elevations, January 1974 (Box 120, Folder 1)
  - Washer Tower Addition Section, Roof Plans, and Details, January 1974 (Box 120, Folder 1)
  - Washer Tower Addition Sections and Details, January 1974 (Box 120, Folder 1)
  - Washer Tower Addition Floor Plan and Sections, January 1974 (Box 120, Folder 1)
  - Piping Plans- First and Second Floor- Main Mill, January 1974 (Box 120, Folder 1)
  - Piping Plan- Third Floor and Details Main Mill, January 1974 (Box 120, Folder 1)
  - Piping Plans for Air Washer Towers Main Mill, January 1974 (Box 120, Folder 1)
  - Washer Tower Addition Section, Roof Plans, and Details, January 1974 (Box 120, Folder 3)
  - Washer Tower Addition Floor Plan and Elevations, January 1974 (Box 120, Folder 3)
  - Washer Tower Addition Floor Plan and Elevations, January 1974 (Box 120, Folder 4)
  - Piping Plan- Third Floor and Details Main Mill, January 1974 (Box 120, Folder 4)
  - Washer Tower Addition Sections and Details, January 1974 (Box 120, Folder 4)
  - Washer Tower Addition Floor Plan and Sections, January 1974 (Box 120, Folder 4)
  - Piping Plans- First and Second Floor- Main Mill, January 1974 (Box 120, Folder 4)
  - Piping Plans for Air Washer Towers Main Mill, January 1974 (Box 120, Folder 4)
  - Phase 1A Site Plan- Legend and Details January 1974, January 1974 (Box 120, Folder 4)
  - Legend Air Washers No. 1 Thru 6 Lighting and Power Plan, January 1974 (Box 120, Folder 4)
  - Panelboard and Lighting Fixture Schedules, Miscellaneous Plans and Details, January 1974 (Box 120, Folder 4)
  - Site Plan, January 1974 (Box 120, Folder 4)
  - Plans, Sections and Details, January 1974 (Box 120, Folder 4)
  - 2nd and 3rd Floor Framing Plan, January 1974 (Box 120, Folder 4)
  - Elevations, January 1974 (Box 120, Folder 4)
  - Column Schedule and Details, January 1974 (Box 120, Folder 4)
  - Floor Plans, January 1974 (Box 120, Folder 4)
  - Section, Roof Plans, and Details, January 1974 (Box 120, Folder 4)
  - Alternate No 1 Washer Tower Addition, June 1974 (Box 120, Folder 3)
  - Sheet No 1-17-7 (Box 122, Folder 1)
  - Sheet [missing] Elevation [missing] (Box 122, Folder 3)
  - Plat of Mill Site Washington Mills (Box 120, Folder 1)
  - Window and Door Details (Main Mill) (Box 121, Folder 1)
  - Plans, Sections, and D [rest of title is missing] (Box 121, Folder 1)
  - Sheet No [missing] Details of [missing] (Box 121, Folder 1)
  - [Title Missing] Machinery Layout (Box 121, Folder 2)
  - Elevations of Washington Mills (Box 122, Folder 1)
  - Elevations of Washington Mills (Box 122, Folder 1)